Our goal is to generate continuous trajectories,
目標は継続してトラジェクトリーを生成することですが
but how do you do that?
それはどうやればいいのでしょうか?
Let's start with a native approach and then gets more realistic.
ネイティブアプローチをはじめて より現実に近づいていきましょう
Let's say, our car has been driving along the road at a constant speed for some time.
車が一定の速度でしばらくの間道路を走行しているとします
The s versus time graph is just a straight line,
速度は定数なので
since the velocity is constant,
s と時間のグラフは直線です
and the differences time graph is flat,
車は同じ真ん中の車線にいるままなので
since the car is just staying in the center of the lane.
異なる時間のグラフは水平です
Also note that I've shifted my axis a bit so that
軸を少し変えてみました
the origin of the frame is our current positioning as TNT.
フレームの原点は TNTのように現在の位置です
This will end up being computationally efficient layer.
これによりあとでコンピュータに効率的なレイヤーを表示することができます
Now let's say we're getting off this highway soon.
ここで もうすぐこの高速を降りるとします
So we want to change lane in order to end up there.
よってそこにたどり着くために車線を変更します
After some delta-T which let's say it's 10 second.
たとえば Δt を 10 秒とします
On the SNT-graph that goal would be here and here.
SNT-グラフでは ゴールはこことここです
The stop position and go position are fixed.
停止位置と開始位置は固定されています
They define what we call the boundary conditions of our trajectory at t equals zero,
t = 0 と t = 0 でのトラジェクトリーの境界条件と呼ばれるものを
and t equals ten.
定義します
If those were our only boundary conditions,
それらだけが境界条件であれば
then we might consider s and t-trajectory is looking like this.
s と t トラジェクトリーはこのような感じだと考えられます
But it turns out that these aren't physically possible.
でも これらは物理的に不可能です
This kink in the slope would translate in
スロープのこの不具合が 無限の加速が必要になる
an instantaneous jumping speed which would require infinite acceleration.
瞬時に跳ね上がる速度に変換します
Now, if we were to send that to our motion control module,
それをモーションコントロールモジュールに送信した場合
maybe they can track this trajectory, but probably not.
このトラジェクトリーを追跡できるかもしれませんが たぶん無理です
And even if they tried to track it,
それを追跡しようとしても
it would result in a very strong acceleration of our car,
車をすごく加速させてしまうだけです
which is both uncomfortable and dangerous.
それは不快で危険です
This is why we need both continuity and smoothness in our trajectories.
これが私たちがトラジェクトリーで連続性とスムーズさの両方を必要とする理由です
But how much continuity and smoothness?
でもどれくらいの継続性とスムーズさが必要になるのでしょうか?
We know we want continuity in position,
車は瞬間移動できないので、
since our car cannot teleport.
位置に連続性が必要です
And it would not make sense to compute a trajectory starting 10 metres ahead of us.
また 10 m 先から始まるトラジェクトリーを計算することは意味がありません
And we also know that our car cannot instantaneously change speed,
また 車は瞬時に速度変更できないことも分かっています
therefore the speed should also be continuous.
よって 速度も継続されるべきです
Following this logic you could also say that the acceleration should be
この理論に従うと、加速度は連続的であるべきであり、
continuous and maybe the acceleration's derivity as well and so on.
かつ加速度の微分値も同様であるべきだと言えるでしょう
Position becomes velocity, velocity because acceleration,
位置は速度になり 速度は加速になり
acceleration becomes jerk, and going even further you get snap, crackle, and pop.
加速はジャークになり さらに スナップ クラックル ポップとなっていきます
It turns out that one of these quantities
これらの単位の 1 つが
is directly related to human perception of comfort.
直接人間の快適さの認知に関連付けられます
So let's think about it.
では考えてみましょう
In a vehicle, humans feel discomfort when which of these values is high?
自動車では いつどの値が高いと人は不快と感じるのでしょうか?
Velocity? No. When they cruise down the highway at high velocity,
速度?いいえ 高速道路を高速で走行すると
people usually don't find it less comfortable than when they drive at lower speed.
低い速度で走行しているときより快適さが減少します
And if you think about airplanes,
飛行機のことを考えてみてください
they move very fast and they aren't really uncomfortable.
非常に高速で動いていますが 不快だとはあまり思いません
Acceleration maybe?
加速度かな?
That's slightly more tricky.
それはもう少し微妙なところです
We are indeed sensitive to acceleration but mostly when it becomes very high.
加速度については本当に敏感ですが ほとんどの場合非常に高速になったときです
For example, we are all used to supporting acceleration up to
たとえば 私たちはみんな サポートしている 1G までの加速度を使用します
one G which is the most you can usually sustain in a normal car.
これは 通常の車で許可されています
Therefore, we shouldn't reach
よって 不快になるほど高速な加速度レベルに
acceleration levels that are high enough to become uncomfortable.
達するべきではありません
Jerk, then? It turns out,
では Jerk はどうでしょうか?
this is the quantity that humans perceive as uncomfortable.
これは人が不快だと感じる量になります
We can tolerate high acceleration but we don't like it
高加速度を許容できますが 瞬時に加速度が変わるときは好みません
when our acceleration changes too quickly which is high jerk.
それが高 jerk です
So when we design trajectories for self-driving car,
自動運転車のトラジェクトリーを設計するとき
we would like it, if they were jerk minimizing.
jerk を最小限にできるようにしたいと考えます